Ting Chung

Savannah, GA 31407 | 678-557-5088 | tchung682@gmail.com GitHub | Blog | Portfolio website | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in aircraft systems engineering. Possess strong skills in web application development and engineering that help technological companies drive efficient and reliable software development. Proficient in reading and writing Chinese. Fluent in Mandarin Chinese.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, and systems engineering.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Prayer journal - Github | Demo

React/Redux front end with Ruby on Rails API allows a user to post rich text journal entries and comment.

- Interactive React user interface allows a user to perform CRUD actions and updates instantly to web the application.
- Client-side routing performed to allow access to nested routes via React Router.
- Utilizes http-only cookies to store JSON web token encrypted user information client-side.
- Stores application state via Redux store allowing universal source of truth.
- Posts entries, comments, and likes via redux-thunk to Rails API using postgreSQL database.

Small groups - Github | Demo

A Javascript/Rails API single page application that allows a user to submit bible study topics.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Leveraged asynchronous Javascript fetch requests to Rails API backend using postgreSQL database.
- Rails API outputs ActiveRecord objects via JSON serializer.
- Used object oriented Javascript classes to encapsulate behavior which results in separation of concerns design pattern.
- Implemented Quill rich text editor to allow users to submit photos and videos along with blog.

Prayer gathering - Github | Demo

A Ruby on Rails web application that allows a user to host prayer gathering events.

- Utilized model-view-controller design pattern resulting in separation of concerns.
- Validated login and event data by creating Rails validation models to ensure persisted data validity.
- Established ActiveRecord many-to-many associations to create join table resulting in object relational mapping of data persisted to postgreSQL database.
- Encrypted user login data persisting salted and hashed password in postgreSQL database.

EXPERIENCE

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

Technical Specialist I

Savannah, GA

05/2012 - 05/2020

- Implemented electrical design solutions for brakes, landing gear, hydraulics, and door systems.
- Investigated and resolved flight test and lab issues through troubleshooting and integration testing.
- Developed brake control system requirements for validation and verification of systems.
- Created Project Timelines, conducted Root Cause Analysis, and Prepared Certification Reports.

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

Savannah, GA

Service Center Coordinator

09/2010 - 05/2012

- Managed international business jet aircraft maintenance visits and aircraft export by ensuring strict project timelines were met.
- Provided maintenance solutions to adhere to rigorous repair station standards.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development program

Online

06/2020 - Present

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor's of Science (BS) in Electrical Engineering

08/2007